<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Home on Christopher Lang</title><link>https://cjlang.github.io/</link><description>Recent content in Home on Christopher Lang</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 23 Aug 2025 07:43:39 -0230</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://cjlang.github.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Memorial Mathematics Working Seminar</title><link>https://cjlang.github.io/seminars/workingseminar/</link><pubDate>Sat, 23 Aug 2025 07:43:39 -0230</pubDate><guid>https://cjlang.github.io/seminars/workingseminar/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;strong>Fall Schedule&lt;/strong>: 2–3 pm in HH 3013&lt;/p>
&lt;table>
&lt;colgroup>
&lt;col style="width: 11%" />
&lt;col style="width: 88%" />
&lt;/colgroup>
&lt;tbody>
&lt;tr class="odd">
&lt;td>&lt;strong>September 30th&lt;/strong>&lt;/td>
&lt;td style="text-align: left;">&lt;strong>Christopher Lang - An introduction
to topological recursion&lt;/strong>&lt;br />
Topological recursion is a construction in algebraic geometry that
recursively computes invariants of spectral curves. It has applications
to enumerative geometry, string theory, knot theory, mathematical
physics, and random matrix theory, among others. I will introduce some
of the main concepts of this construction.&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;/tbody>
&lt;/table></description></item><item><title>Fixed points on moduli spaces</title><link>https://cjlang.github.io/ancillaries/modulispacethm/</link><pubDate>Tue, 30 Jul 2024 07:43:39 -0230</pubDate><guid>https://cjlang.github.io/ancillaries/modulispacethm/</guid><description>&lt;p>Below we list the main results and examples from my paper “Fixed
points of Lie group actions on moduli spaces: A tale of two actions”.
Theorem 1.1 originally appeared in my &lt;a
href="https://hdl.handle.net/10012/20906">thesis&lt;/a> as Theorem 1.1.1. I
discussed this result during my talk at the &lt;a
href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=a5dZKpBPkxQ&amp;amp;">Geometric Models
of Matter Conference&lt;/a> in 2024.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The results in this paper allow us to study &lt;a
href="https://cjlang.github.io/ancillaries/euclidmono/">Euclidean monopoles&lt;/a>, &lt;a
href="https://cjlang.github.io/ancillaries/hypermono/">hyperbolic monopoles&lt;/a>, and &lt;a
href="https://cjlang.github.io/ancillaries/instantons/">instantons&lt;/a> with continuous
symmetries. However, it is a general result that can also be used
outside of gauge theory to easily find fixed points of Lie group actions
on moduli spaces. These applications comprise the majority of my &lt;a
href="https://hdl.handle.net/10012/20906">thesis&lt;/a>.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Instantons with continuous conformal symmetries</title><link>https://cjlang.github.io/ancillaries/instantons/</link><pubDate>Wed, 14 Aug 2024 10:43:39 -0230</pubDate><guid>https://cjlang.github.io/ancillaries/instantons/</guid><description>&lt;p>Below we list the main results and examples from my paper “Instantons
with continuous conformal symmetries: Hyperbolic and singular monopoles
and more, oh my!” Other than Proposition 3.4, this work originally
appeared as Chapter 3 of my &lt;a
href="https://hdl.handle.net/10012/20906">thesis&lt;/a>. I discussed this
work during my talk at the &lt;a
href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=a5dZKpBPkxQ&amp;amp;">Geometric Models
of Matter Conference&lt;/a> in 2024.&lt;/p>
&lt;h1 id="summary">Summary&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>We classify the various continuous symmetries that an instanton can
possess. We then linearize the symmetry equation for each continuous
symmetry. By using representation theory, we can solve these linear
equations given any representation. This makes the process of finding
novel examples of instantons with higher rank structure groups much
easier. In fact, for some symmetries, we know every example of
instantons with that symmetry. Additionally, instantons with a variety
of continuous symmetries are related to other gauge theoretic objects,
so by investigating these symmetric instantons, we can better understand
these other objects.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Hyperbolic monopoles with continuous symmetries</title><link>https://cjlang.github.io/ancillaries/hypermono/</link><pubDate>Thu, 15 Aug 2024 11:43:39 -0230</pubDate><guid>https://cjlang.github.io/ancillaries/hypermono/</guid><description>&lt;p>Below we list the main results and examples from my paper “Hyperbolic
monopoles with continuous symmetries”.&lt;/p>
&lt;h1 id="summary">Summary&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>By linearizing the symmetry equations and using representation
theory, we identify many novel examples of hyperbolic monopoles with
higher rank structure groups. In fact, in the paper, we identify many
infinite families of spherically symmetric, hyperbolic monopoles with
varying rank structure groups. These monopoles have interesting
properties; in Example 2 below, we identify a spherically symmetric
&lt;span class="math inline">\(\mathrm{Sp}(4)\)&lt;/span> hyperbolic monopole
that vanishes nowhere.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Euclidean monopoles with continuous symmetries</title><link>https://cjlang.github.io/ancillaries/euclidmono/</link><pubDate>Fri, 16 Aug 2024 07:43:39 -0230</pubDate><guid>https://cjlang.github.io/ancillaries/euclidmono/</guid><description>&lt;p>Below we list the main results and examples from my joint paper
“Construction of Nahm data and BPS monopoles with continuous
symmetries”, including improvements mentioned in my paper “Hyperbolic
monopoles with continuous symmetries”.&lt;/p>
&lt;h1 id="summary">Summary&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>By linearizing the symmetry equations and using representation
theory, we identify many novel examples of Euclidean monopoles with
higher rank structure groups and non-maximal symmetry breaking. In the
paper, we identify many infinite families of spherically symmetric,
Euclidean monopoles with varying rank structure groups.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Symmetry breaking of monopoles</title><link>https://cjlang.github.io/ancillaries/symbreak/</link><pubDate>Wed, 28 Aug 2024 07:43:39 -0230</pubDate><guid>https://cjlang.github.io/ancillaries/symbreak/</guid><description>&lt;p>Below we list the main results and examples from Section 2.3 of my &lt;a
href="https://hdl.handle.net/10012/20906">thesis&lt;/a>: “Symmetry
breaking”.&lt;/p>
&lt;h1 id="summary">Summary&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>We identify the symmetry breaking of monopoles, part of their
topological classification. In particular, for monopoles with structure
group a Lie group with a classical, simple Lie algebra, we provide
simple classifications based on eigenvalues of the Higgs field at
infinity.&lt;/p>
&lt;h1 id="introduction">Introduction&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>Let &lt;span class="math inline">\(G\)&lt;/span> be a compact, connected,
real Lie group and &lt;span class="math inline">\(M\)&lt;/span> a connected,
geodesically complete three-manifold with infinite injectivity radius at
some point. Let &lt;span class="math inline">\((\Phi,A)\)&lt;/span> be a
monopole on &lt;span class="math inline">\(M.\)&lt;/span> That is, the pair
satisfies the Bogomolny equations and a finite energy condition.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Representation theory of Lie algebras</title><link>https://cjlang.github.io/ancillaries/reptheory/</link><pubDate>Fri, 30 Aug 2024 01:43:39 -0230</pubDate><guid>https://cjlang.github.io/ancillaries/reptheory/</guid><description>&lt;p>In the following documents, we outline some lesser-known results from
the representation theory of Lie algebras. Together, these documents
constitute Appendix D of my &lt;a
href="https://hdl.handle.net/10012/20906">thesis&lt;/a>. However, they are
separated here for readers interested in individual topics and for ease
of reading.&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="https://cjlang.github.io/Lang_RealAndQuaternionic.pdf">Real and quaternionic
representations&lt;/a>&lt;br />
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="https://cjlang.github.io/Lang_DualReps.pdf">Representations and their
duals&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="https://cjlang.github.io/Lang_DirectSum.pdf">Representations of direct sums&lt;/a>
(focusing on representations of &lt;span
class="math inline">\(\mathfrak{so}(4)\simeq\mathfrak{sp}(1)\oplus\mathfrak{sp}(1)\)&lt;/span>)&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul></description></item><item><title>Teaching</title><link>https://cjlang.github.io/teaching/</link><pubDate>Mon, 29 Jul 2024 22:17:27 -0230</pubDate><guid>https://cjlang.github.io/teaching/</guid><description>&lt;p>I am always trying to improve my teaching skills. Here is a list of
the teaching qualifications that I have completed:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Certificate in University Teaching, 2021 - 2022&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Fundamentals in University Teaching, 2020&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Certificate in Online Course Facilitation, 2020&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>During the Certificate in University Teaching Program, I conducted a
literature review focused on understanding and mitigating student
resistance to active learning. If you are interested, feel free to read
my report &lt;a
href="https://cjlang.github.io/Student_Resistance_to_Active_Learning.pdf">here&lt;/a>.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Research</title><link>https://cjlang.github.io/research/</link><pubDate>Mon, 29 Jul 2024 22:13:36 -0230</pubDate><guid>https://cjlang.github.io/research/</guid><description>&lt;p>My main research interests are Lie theory, representation theory,
moduli spaces, and gauge theory—specifically instantons and
monopoles.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="published-papers">Published Papers&lt;/h2>
&lt;h3
id="hyperbolic-monopoles-with-continuous-symmetries-j.-geom.-phys.-203-105258-2024.-doi-arxiv-main-results">“Hyperbolic
monopoles with continuous symmetries”, J. Geom. Phys. 203, 105258
(2024). &lt;a
href="https://doi.org/10.1016/j.geomphys.2024.105258">DOI&lt;/a>, &lt;a
href="https://arxiv.org/abs/2310.10626">arXiv&lt;/a>, &lt;a
href="https://cjlang.github.io/ancillaries/hypermono/">Main results&lt;/a>&lt;/h3>
&lt;details>
&lt;summary>
&lt;strong>Abstract&lt;/strong>
&lt;/summary>
&lt;p>
We provide a framework to classify hyperbolic monopoles with continuous
symmetries and find a Structure Theorem, greatly simplifying the
construction of all those with spherically symmetry. In doing so, we
reduce the problem of finding spherically symmetric hyperbolic monopoles
to a problem in representation theory. Additionally, we determine
constraints on the structure groups of such monopoles. Using these
results, we construct novel spherically symmetric &lt;span
class="math inline">\(\mathrm{Sp}(n)\)&lt;/span> hyperbolic monopoles.
&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>