<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Ancillaries on Christopher Lang</title><link>https://cjlang.github.io/ancillaries/</link><description>Recent content in Ancillaries on Christopher Lang</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 30 Aug 2024 01:43:39 -0230</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://cjlang.github.io/ancillaries/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Fixed points on moduli spaces</title><link>https://cjlang.github.io/ancillaries/modulispacethm/</link><pubDate>Tue, 30 Jul 2024 07:43:39 -0230</pubDate><guid>https://cjlang.github.io/ancillaries/modulispacethm/</guid><description>Below we list the main results and examples from my paper “Fixed points of Lie group actions on moduli spaces: A tale of two actions”. Theorem 1.1 originally appeared in my thesis as Theorem 1.1.1. I discussed this result during my talk at the Geometric Models of Matter Conference in 2024.
The results in this paper allow us to study Euclidean monopoles, hyperbolic monopoles, and instantons with continuous symmetries. However, it is a general result that can also be used outside of gauge theory to easily find fixed points of Lie group actions on moduli spaces.</description></item><item><title>Instantons with continuous conformal symmetries</title><link>https://cjlang.github.io/ancillaries/instantons/</link><pubDate>Wed, 14 Aug 2024 10:43:39 -0230</pubDate><guid>https://cjlang.github.io/ancillaries/instantons/</guid><description>Below we list the main results and examples from my paper “Instantons with continuous conformal symmetries: Hyperbolic and singular monopoles and more, oh my!” Other than Proposition 3.4, this work originally appeared as Chapter 3 of my thesis. I discussed this work during my talk at the Geometric Models of Matter Conference in 2024.
Summary We classify the various continuous symmetries that an instanton can possess. We then linearize the symmetry equation for each continuous symmetry.</description></item><item><title>Hyperbolic monopoles with continuous symmetries</title><link>https://cjlang.github.io/ancillaries/hypermono/</link><pubDate>Thu, 15 Aug 2024 11:43:39 -0230</pubDate><guid>https://cjlang.github.io/ancillaries/hypermono/</guid><description>Below we list the main results and examples from my paper “Hyperbolic monopoles with continuous symmetries”.
Summary By linearizing the symmetry equations and using representation theory, we identify many novel examples of hyperbolic monopoles with higher rank structure groups. In fact, in the paper, we identify many infinite families of spherically symmetric, hyperbolic monopoles with varying rank structure groups. These monopoles have interesting properties; in Example 2 below, we identify a spherically symmetric \(\mathrm{Sp}(4)\) hyperbolic monopole that vanishes nowhere.</description></item><item><title>Euclidean monopoles with continuous symmetries</title><link>https://cjlang.github.io/ancillaries/euclidmono/</link><pubDate>Fri, 16 Aug 2024 07:43:39 -0230</pubDate><guid>https://cjlang.github.io/ancillaries/euclidmono/</guid><description>Below we list the main results and examples from my joint paper “Construction of Nahm data and BPS monopoles with continuous symmetries”, including improvements mentioned in my paper “Hyperbolic monopoles with continuous symmetries”.
Summary By linearizing the symmetry equations and using representation theory, we identify many novel examples of Euclidean monopoles with higher rank structure groups and non-maximal symmetry breaking. In the paper, we identify many infinite families of spherically symmetric, Euclidean monopoles with varying rank structure groups.</description></item><item><title>Symmetry breaking of monopoles</title><link>https://cjlang.github.io/ancillaries/symbreak/</link><pubDate>Wed, 28 Aug 2024 07:43:39 -0230</pubDate><guid>https://cjlang.github.io/ancillaries/symbreak/</guid><description>Below we list the main results and examples from Section 2.3 of my thesis: “Symmetry breaking”.
Summary We identify the symmetry breaking of monopoles, part of their topological classification. In particular, for monopoles with structure group a Lie group with a classical, simple Lie algebra, we provide simple classifications based on eigenvalues of the Higgs field at infinity.
Introduction Let \(G\) be a compact, connected, real Lie group and \(M\) a connected, geodesically complete three-manifold with infinite injectivity radius at some point.</description></item><item><title>Representation theory of Lie algebras</title><link>https://cjlang.github.io/ancillaries/reptheory/</link><pubDate>Fri, 30 Aug 2024 01:43:39 -0230</pubDate><guid>https://cjlang.github.io/ancillaries/reptheory/</guid><description>In the following documents, we outline some lesser-known results from the representation theory of Lie algebras. Together, these documents constitute Appendix D of my thesis. However, they are separated here for readers interested in individual topics and for ease of reading.
Real and quaternionic representations
Representations and their duals Representations of direct sums (focusing on representations of \(\mathfrak{so}(4)\simeq\mathfrak{sp}(1)\oplus\mathfrak{sp}(1)\))</description></item></channel></rss>